Hilya Auli Fesmia

Design Portfolio Website • +62 851 6350 1230 • hilyafesmia@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/hilyafesmia

HIGHLIGHT

With over 4 years of experience, I have worked across diverse industries, including education, legal, logistics, and influencer marketing, dealing with both customer-facing and B2B platforms. My analytical skills and background in computer science allow me to translate user needs into practical and data-driven designs which improve conversion rates, engagement, and efficiency.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Social Club (Influencer Marketing Agency) | Product Designer

May 2023 - July 2024

- Designed its mobile app for influencers, improving conversion rates by up to 28%.
- Revamped the analytics dashboard to improve operational efficiency and informed strategic decision-making by providing transparent and actionable insights into influencer performance.
- Created its design system, improving design efficiency and ensuring brand consistency.
- The technology division contract was not renewed due to a pivot in business.

GudangAda (SMEs B2B Marketplace) | **Product Designer** @ **Logistics Tribe** Sept 2022 – Apr 2023

- Collaborated with ops to streamline picking up items and returning GMV between drivers and sellers to reduce dispute numbers.
- Designed a system that allowed drivers to notify ops and BD of delayed GMV returns to reduce backfilling work by the ops team and provide faster response time to Seller complaints.
- Was laid off along with the rest of the design team and the logistics division.

Justika (Legal Marketplace) | Product Designer @ Retail Tribe

Dec 2021 – Aug 2022

- Revamped chatroom landing page by adding chatbot-like FAQ, improved number of paying users (NPU) by 39%.
- Revamped business landing page website layout and navigation menus, increased conversion rate (CVR) by 44%, and traffic to previously neglected pages.
- Maintained its design system
- Was laid off due to the closure of the technology division.

SejutaCita (Education) | Product Designer

Jan 2021 – Nov 2021

- As a solo designer, I was responsible for all aspects of product design, from constructing the design system, user research, design, and implementation.
- Redesigned its mobile app's overall experience, structure, and interface and improved click-through rate (CTR) by 65%.

Internship Experiences | UI/UX Designer, UX Researcher, Front-end Developer | May 2018 – Aug 2019

- Dekoruma Collaborated in designing a tracking system used by the interior design team, designed the edit profile feature and crafted empty and error pages for the marketplace.
- Bagidata Conducted primary (quantitative, qualitative) and desk research for the Design Team
- AdaTeman Developed company profile and CRUD system for dashboard using React Redux

EDUCATION

Universitas Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia

2016 - 2020

Bachelor of Computer Science, Major in Computer Science

SKILLS

- Design System
- Mobile & Web Design
- Wireframe

- Prototype
- Data Analytics
- User Research

- Problem-solving
- Figma & Sketch
- HTML & CSS